(my perfect stranger)
(나의 완벽한 낯선 사람)
(Kim Dong-wook)
(김동욱)
(Kim Ki-joo)
(김기주)
(my perfect stranger)
(나의 완벽한 낯선 사람)
(part 1)
(1 부)
When I think back it was a strange night.
돌이켜보면 참 이상한 밤이었다.
The vehicle is leaving the road. I'm going to change my route
차량이 도로를 떠나고 있습니다. 경로를 변경하겠습니다.
Calculate new route.
새로운 경로를 계산합니다.
Everything that day was twisted in the most natural way
그날의 모든 것은 가장 자연스럽게 뒤틀려 있었어
This doesn't happen every day.
이런 일이 매일 일어나는 것은 아닙니다.
Crazy GPS system for bad weather
악천후에 대비한 미친 GPS 시스템
and mobile phone
그리고 휴대폰
(Yin Haejun)
(인해준)
That's when it popped up in front of me.
그 때 그것이 내 앞에 나타났습니다.
oh oh!
오, 오!
Ouch!
아야!
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(서울모 0508)
(time travel system)
(시간여행 시스템)
(Time Travel System User Manual)
(시간여행 시스템 사용설명서)
There is an explanatory manual inside. How to use time machine
안쪽에는 설명 매뉴얼이 들어있습니다. 타임머신 사용법
Yes
예
The kind in novels or movies. A time machine like this.
소설이나 영화에 나오는 종류. 이런 타임머신.
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
I have been a journalist for seven years.
저는 언론인으로 일한 지 7년이 되었습니다.
I only pursue facts.
나는 사실만을 추구합니다.
This is too idealistic for me.
이것은 나에게 너무 이상주의적이다.
What kind of fantasy drama is this the protagonist of?
이게 무슨 판타지 드라마의 주인공이야?
I'm not interested in playing.
나는 노는 것에 관심이 없습니다.
But there is one factor I overlooked.
그런데 제가 간과한 요소가 하나 있습니다.
Curiosity led to my own nemesis.
호기심은 나 자신의 천적으로 이어졌습니다.
(Time Travel System, 2021)
(시간여행시스템, 2021)
(Time and space travel system, 3089)
(시간과 공간 여행 시스템, 3089)
(User Manual)
(사용자 매뉴얼)
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(서울모 0508)
The year 3089, do you want to know what I saw that year?
3089년, 그 해에 내가 무엇을 보았는지 알고 싶나요?
That thing is not important. But what happens next is different.
그 일은 중요하지 않습니다. 그러나 다음에 일어날 일은 다릅니다.
(Time Travel System, 2021)
(시간여행시스템, 2021)
(Time travel system, 2037)
(시간여행 시스템, 2037)
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(서울모 0508)
What will I see in 2037?
2037년에는 무엇을 보게 될까요?
What did I see there...
나는 거기서 무엇을 보았는가...
what exactly is it?
정확히 무엇입니까?
What do you see there?
거기에서 무엇이 보이나요?
have no idea
전혀 모른다
Anyway, after that incident
아무튼 그 사건 이후
My life started to go off track.
내 인생은 궤도에서 벗어나기 시작했습니다.
You see, I'm just here to talk nonsense. Now let's hear it.
알다시피, 나는 단지 말도 안되는 이야기를 하러 여기에 온 것뿐입니다. 이제 들어보자.
(supermarket)
(슈퍼마켓)
I think my uncle has gone crazy.
내 생각엔 삼촌이 미친 것 같아.
(Congratulations on becoming the host of the 1988 Seoul Olympics)
( 1988년 서울올림픽 개최를 ​​축하합니다 )
What a pity, just listen to his uncle.
안타깝지만 삼촌의 말을 들어보세요.
Do you still have what I just gave you?
내가 방금 준 것을 아직도 가지고 있나요?
Yes
예
I'll come back later to pay.
나중에 결제하러 다시 올게요.
If you want to eat something, eat it.
먹고 싶은 게 있으면 먹어보세요.
- See you in 15 minutes. - Yeah.
- 15분 후에 봐요 - 네
Friendly Neighbors Let the Village...
친절한 이웃들에게 마을을 맡겨주세요...
It's a better place to live.
살기에 더 좋은 곳이에요.
More and more teenagers are becoming addicted to hallucinogens.
점점 더 많은 십대들이 환각제에 중독되고 있습니다.
From glue and butane gas
접착제와 부탄가스로부터
It comes in the form of bleach and benzene.
표백제와 벤젠의 형태로 제공됩니다.
Has emerged as a new drug among teenagers
10대들 사이에서 신약으로 떠올랐다
Come and listen to the special report. from another reporter
오셔서 특별보고를 들어보세요. 다른 기자한테서
( BTW, My Perfect Stranger, Episode 1, 1987)
( 그런데, 나의 완벽한 낯선 사람, 에피소드 1, 1987)
I know you are really dedicated.
나는 당신이 정말 헌신적이라는 것을 알고 있습니다.
- You take good care of the old man. - Oh my God.
- 노인을 잘 돌보시네요 - 맙소사.
- Oh - I really want to thank you.
- 아 - 정말 감사드리고 싶습니다.
- Oh come on - Oh my God.
- 아, 어서 - 맙소사.
- Let's have a drink - Yes
- 한잔 하자 - 응
Okay, everyone.
좋아요, 여러분.
as we all know
우리 모두 알고 있듯이
Our Yujing Village was selected...
우리 유징마을이 선정되었습니다...
Create a crime-free village for five consecutive years
5년 연속 범죄 없는 마을 만들기
Hey, there's clean water and it's peaceful.
아, 물도 깨끗하고 평화롭네요.
Is this a good place to live? Do you all agree?
이곳이 살기 좋은 곳인가요? 다들 동의하시나요?
- Agreed - Of course.
- 동의해요 - 물론이죠.
Let's drink.
마시자.
Is he an award winner?
그 사람이 수상자인가?
I really enjoy being the center of attention.
나는 관심의 중심이 되는 것을 정말 좋아한다.
Mazuto
진렬한 사람
Brothers too
형제들도
- It's nice to see him happy. - It's good for the ghost.
- 행복한 모습이 보기 좋네요 - 유령에게도 좋은 일이군요.
The Village that Makes Us It's a great place to live.
우리를 만드는 마을 살기 좋은 곳입니다.
most important player
가장 중요한 선수
and be respected by everyone in our village
그리고 우리 마을의 모든 사람들 로부터 존경을 받으세요
- The light of our people - Oh my God!
- 우리 민족의 빛 - 맙소사!
Please meet Principal Yoon Byung-koo...
윤병구 교장을 만나보세요..
and our committee chair
그리고 우리 위원회 위원장
- Oh my god - Go ahead.
- 맙소사 - 어서요.
- This guy said you don't have to do this. - No.
- 이 사람이 그러지 않아도 된다고 하더군요 - 아니요
- Say something - Come on
- 뭐라고 말해봐 - 어서
- What does the principal have to say? - Yes.
- 교장은 뭐라고 말하나요? - 예.
Oh, thank you.
오 감사합니다.
- Great
- 좋아 좋아
But I did nothing.
그러나 나는 아무것도 하지 않았다.
First of all, I want to thank the villagers. Yuting Village
우선 마을 주민들에게 감사의 말씀을 전하고 싶습니다. 유팅 마을
Very good people are capital.
아주 좋은 사람들은 자본입니다.
second
두번째
I want to thank our children for growing into such wonderful people.
우리 아이들이 이렇게 멋진 사람으로 성장해줘서 고맙다는 말을 전하고 싶습니다 .
This is simply not true.
이것은 사실이 아닙니다.
No wonder it ended in tragedy.
비극으로 끝난 것도 당연합니다 .
Because even though we know very little about each other
왜냐하면 우리는 서로에 대해 아는 바가 거의 없음에도 불구하고
But you still believe each other with your eyes closed.
하지만 당신은 여전히 ​​눈을 감고 서로를 믿고 있습니다.
What are you talking about him?
그 사람에 대해 무슨 말을하는거야?
- what did he say? - How is this going?
- 그는 무엇을 말 했는가? - 어떻게 되어가나요?
About 30 seconds later
약 30초 후
You will hear a scream. It came from the mountains behind.
비명 소리가 들릴 것입니다. 그것은 뒤에 있는 산에서 왔습니다.
Six naughty teenagers...
여섯 명의 장난꾸러기 십대들...
They will begin to split up and run in six directions.
그들은 갈라져 여섯 방향으로 달리기 시작할 것입니다.
Everyone was super drunk.
다들 엄청 취했어요.
And three of these six are girls from this village.
여섯 명 중 세 명은 이 마을 여자아이예요.
What is he saying?
쟤 뭐래?
Are there any children in our village who are drunk after drinking glue?
우리 마을에는 접착제를 마시고 취한 아이들이 있나요?
Maybe not?
아마?
Television reporters had clues before the incident.
텔레비전 기자들은 사건 이전에 단서를 가지고 있었습니다.
Departing from Seoul
서울 출발
- TV reporter?
- TV 기자요?
Five minutes later, the reporter arrived.
5분 뒤 기자가 도착했다.
You have approximately 4 minutes and 30 seconds.
대략 4분 30초 정도 남았습니다.
You need to solve this problem. before reporters arrived
이 문제를 해결해야 합니다. 기자들이 도착하기 전에
Who are you? You don't look like anyone here.
누구세요? 당신은 여기 누구와도 닮지 않은 것 같아요.
How dare you interrupt? Our picnic and such accusations
어떻게 감히 방해합니까? 우리의 소풍과 그런 비난
Kim Hae- kyung, sixth grader, one room, Woojeong High School
김해경 6학년 우정고등학교 원룸
My middle daughter was in that room.
내 둘째 딸이 그 방에 있었어요.
- My classmate Lee Eun Ha - My Eun Ha?
- 같은 반 친구 이은하 - 내은하?
Our sweet little girl?
우리 귀여운 딸?
Another classmate, Park Yuri
또 다른 동급생 박유리
Wait, that's my niece.
잠깐만요, 저 사람은 제 조카예요.
Are you sure you want to take the risk?
위험을 감수하시겠습니까?
According to the Toxic Substances Control Act...
유해물질 관리법에 따르면...
- What? - What's that sound?
- 무엇? - 그게 무슨 소리야?
- Is that the sound of people screaming? - Yes, it's coming from over there.
- 사람들이 비명을 지르는 소리인가요? - 네, 저쪽에서 들려요.
Has it been 30 seconds?
30초쯤 됐나?
This story is about our children.
이 이야기는 우리 아이들에 관한 이야기입니다.
Let's believe him.
그를 믿어보자.
No, that's not true at all.
아니요, 전혀 사실이 아닙니다.
I did nothing.
나는 아무것도 하지 않았다.
Oh my god.
맙소사.
Drink, the water here is still clean.
마셔보세요. 여기 물은 아직 깨끗해요.
Who are you?
누구세요?
Missed a step on the cliff over there…
저기 절벽에서 한걸음도 놓쳤네요...
It was her destiny to end her life at the age of 19 .
19세에 생을 마감하는 것은 그녀의 운명이었다 .
I just changed it to
방금 다음과 같이 바꿨습니다.
Who are you...
누구세요...
very handsome
아주 잘생겼다
- What's this? Hey, good girl... - Eun-ha, oh my god.
- 이게 뭐죠? 안녕 착한 아이... - 은하야, 맙소사.
- Unbelievable, you crazy kid. - Galaxy
- 말도 안 돼, 미친 새끼야. - 갤럭시
- This kid - Oh my God.
- 이 아이는 - 맙소사.
- Please calm down - you crazy person.
- 진정하세요 - 미친놈아.
- pay attention - oh, look at that
- 주의하세요 - 아, 저거 좀 보세요
- This is unbelievable. - Let's go.
- 말도 안 돼 - 가자
Go straight and hurry up.
똑바로 가서 서두르세요.
- Come on. - Here.
- 여기 로 와요 .
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
- Attention - Grandma, grandpa.
- 주목 - 할머니, 할아버지.
- What did you do... what did you do? - What?
- 무슨 짓을 한 거야... 무슨 짓을 한 거야? - 무엇?
- Oh my God, what happened?
- 맙소사, 무슨 일이 일어난 거야?
Come quickly.
빨리 오세요.
- Come on oh my God - Let's go
- 어서 맙소사 - 가자
- come here - stop
- 이리와 - 그만해
- He... - What?
- 그 사람은... - 뭐?
Do I need to push?
밀어야 하나요?
The one who tricks other kids into smelling glue is you.
다른 아이들을 속여 접착제 냄새를 맡게 하는 사람은 바로 당신입니다.
She may make herself appear to be in danger.
그녀는 자신이 위험에 처한 것처럼 보일 수도 있습니다.
But others actually had to die.
그러나 다른 사람들은 실제로 죽어야 했습니다.
I don’t want to help a misbehaving kid. Who killed two of his own friends?
나는 버릇없는 아이를 돕고 싶지 않습니다. 자신의 친구 두 명을 죽인 사람은 누구입니까?
If you really want this, just say so.
정말로 이것을 원한다면 그렇게 말하세요.
I'll help you push it down.
밀어내실 수 있도록 도와드리겠습니다.
What is this bastard?
이 새끼는 뭐야?
Can you forget about it for a while?
잠시 잊을 수 있나요?
("10 out of 10 glue sniffers killed two people")
("접착제 냄새를 맡는 사람 10명 중 10명이 2명을 죽였습니다.")
Wait a moment.
잠시만 기다려주세요.
Let's go and see.
가서 보자.
Oh, I was totally shocked.
아, 완전 충격받았어요.
- Oh my God - Damn, they survived.
- 맙소사 - 젠장, 그들은 살아남았어.
He saved her.
그는 그녀를 구했습니다.
Because your mother is different from other people. So I think my life is very difficult.
왜냐하면 당신의 어머니는 다른 사람들과 다르기 때문입니다. 그래서 내 인생이 참 힘든 것 같아요.
What?
무엇?
What do you want to know?
무엇을 알고 싶나요?
Although her mother was a little different, she...
엄마는 조금 달랐지만...
I live for you.
난 너를 위해서 살아.
So don't do such a thing. with friends again
그러니 그런 짓은 하지 마세요. 다시 친구들과
do you understand?
이해했나요?
I don't want to do that either.
나도 그러고 싶지 않아요.
even without you
너 없이도
There are still people in this village who are helping. there are more
아직도 이 마을에는 도움을 주시는 분들이 계십니다. 더있다
Wow!
우와!
- Hello - Hero of Yujing Village
- 안녕하세요 - 위징마을의 영웅
Astonishing.
놀라운.
the best.
최고.
Above knows who to send to us.
위에는 우리에게 보낼 사람이 누구인지 알고 있습니다.
("Wujing Village was selected as the village that has been crime-free for five consecutive years)
("우징촌, 5년 연속 무범죄 마을 로 선정 )
Oh, Dad.
아, 아빠.
Oh my gosh, did you just remember that?
맙소사, 방금 그거 기억났어?
The next news story is about unruly teenagers.
다음 뉴스 기사는 다루기 힘든 십대들에 관한 것입니다.
has become a serious social problem
심각한 사회 문제로 떠올랐다
Here are high school students who get drunk on glue.
여기 접착제에 취한 고등학생이 있습니다.
Oh my God, where have they all gone?
맙소사, 그 사람들 다 어디로 갔나요?
God, be careful.
하느님, 조심하세요.
Ouch!
아야!
How can we thank you enough?
어떻게 감사해야 할까요?
This is just a temporary illusion.
이것은 단지 일시적인 환상일 뿐입니다.
They were still in high school.
그들은 아직 고등학생이었습니다.
Parents should comfort and guide them well.
부모는 그들을 잘 위로하고 지도해야 합니다.
Because that's what adults should do.
그게 어른들이 해야 할 일이니까.
You said exactly what I thought.
제가 생각한 것과 정확히 같은 말씀을 하셨습니다.
You know these things. How are you?
당신은 이런 것들을 알고 있습니다. 어떻게 지내세요?
Know exactly what will happen when.
언제 무슨 일이 일어날지 정확히 알아보세요.
It all happened like that.
모든 일이 그렇게 일어났습니다.
That's it.
그게 다야.
-Uncle- Oh.
-삼촌- 아.
Hidehiro Hidezen
히데히로 히데요시
Teacher, you just dropped it.
선생님, 방금 떨어뜨리셨어요.
I?
나?
(Teaching Certificate)
(강의증명서)
- Pretty much the same thing. - What?
- 거의 똑같아 - 뭐?
I put it down.
나는 그것을 내려놓았다.
Oh, really.
오, 진짜.
Teacher Yoon Haejun?
윤해준선생님?
Are you a teacher?
당신은 교사입니까?
Yes
예
He accidentally moved from Seoul. The time to come to our village is just right.
그는 우연히 서울에서 이사했다. 우리 마을에 올 시간이 딱 맞습니다.
- What? - Really?
- 무엇? - 정말?
That is...
그건...
Sorry for asking.
여쭤 보아서 죄송하지만.
But have you found a new job?
그런데 새 직장을 구하셨나요?
Not yet, not yet.
아직은 아니야, 아직은 아니야.
There is a vacancy at the school I am currently in charge of .
현재 제가 담당하고 있는 학교에 공석이 생겼습니다 .
- Oh, is that right? - Yes.
- 아, 그렇죠? - 예.
What kind of coincidence could this be?
이게 무슨 우연의 일치일까요?
I teach Korean.
나는 한국어를 가르친다.
Yes, Teacher Yin.
네, 이은 선생님.
This was the beginning of my fake life.
이것이 나의 가짜 인생의 시작이었다.
In 1987, in that village
1987년, 그 마을에서
(teacher's office)
(교무실)
(Korean language)
(한국어)
- Teacher, - go away.
- 선생님, - 가세요.
Go away.
저리 가요.
I'm the first one here, teacher.
제가 처음 왔습니다, 선생님.
teacher
선생님
I've become someone I never wanted to be.
나는 결코 되고 싶지 않았던 사람이 되었습니다 .
That's the teacher
그 분이 선생님이에요
and bought a house in a remote village
그리고 외딴 마을에 집을 샀어요
Something I never wanted to buy before.
예전에는 사고 싶지 않았던 물건.
I lived like this for a whole month.
나는 한 달 동안 이렇게 살았습니다.
Why do I have to do this?
왜 내가 이 일을 해야 합니까?
(Seoul 2021)
(서울 2021)
The Yujing Village Serial Murder Case happened in 1987
1987년 위징촌 연쇄살인 사건
The man you killed 34 years ago...
34년 전에 당신이 죽인 남자...
Still alive in that place
아직도 그 곳에 살아있어
No, I didn't kill them.
아니요, 저는 그들을 죽이지 않았습니다.
I know.
알아요.
What?
무엇?
That's why I went there. Find out the real culprit
그래서 내가 거기에 갔다. 진짜 범인을 알아내세요
This way you and I can survive.
그래야 너와 내가 살아남을 수 있다.
what are you saying?
당신이 무슨 말을하는거야?
You'll be released tomorrow morning , right?
내일 아침에 석방되겠죠 ?
Let's meet in Yujing Village.
유징마을에서 만나요.
I'll tell you what I'm talking about.
내가 말하는 내용을 말씀 드리겠습니다.
Then before tomorrow morning...
그럼 내일 아침까지...
This also helps with survival.
이는 생존에도 도움이 됩니다.
("The murderer of the Youjing Village serial murder case committed suicide")
("유징촌 연쇄살인사건의 살인범이 스스로 목숨을 끊었다")
("The murderer of the Gojing Village serial murder case will be released tomorrow.")
("고징마을 연쇄살인사건의 범인은 내일 공개됩니다.")
Mr. Yunyong, where are you?
윤용 씨, 어디 계세요?
Is it coming?
오고 있나요?
(Editor-in-Chief)
(편집장)
I know today is your holiday.
오늘이 당신의 휴일이라는 걸 알아요.
But the teacher only called Teacher Yin Ying. what can I do?
그런데 선생님은 윤영 선생님한테만 전화를 했어요. 어떡해?
I will arrive soon.
나는 곧 도착할 것이다.
I realized I couldn't rest.
나는 쉴 수 없다는 것을 깨달았다.
(Mother)
(어머니)
what else?
또 뭐야?
Is it a video this time?
이번에는 영상인가요?
What is this about?
이것은 무엇에 관한 것입니까?
This is the video.
이것은 비디오입니다.
Singing was very cute when I was a child .
어렸을 때 노래하는 게 너무 귀여웠어요 .
Mom was worried because it was swollen.
엄마는 부어서 걱정했어요.
My son told me to convert it to a file. You can put it in a USB.
아들이 파일로 변환하라고 했어요. USB에 넣으시면 됩니다.
I understand, I will do the same next time.
이해합니다. 다음에도 똑같이 할게요.
I committed to doing this for over a year.
나는 이 일을 1년 넘게 하겠다고 다짐했다.
I didn't forget on purpose.
일부러 잊지는 않았어요.
Are you still busy these days?
요즘도 여전히 바쁘나요?
My child must be very tired.
우리 아이가 많이 피곤할 것 같아요.
But how late is it now? Are you going home today?
그런데 지금은 얼마나 늦었나요? 오늘 집에 갈 거야?
today?
오늘?
Why do we celebrate our father’s birthday every year?
왜 우리는 매년 아버지의 생일을 축하합니까?
Mom used to get flowers from him. On your birthday?
엄마는 그에게서 꽃을 사곤 했어요. 너의 생일에?
He rarely comes home.
그는 집에 거의 오지 않습니다.
Preparing food for him was always just the two of us.
그를 위해 음식을 준비하는 일은 늘 우리 둘뿐이었다.
Because his father is very busy.
왜냐하면 그의 아버지는 매우 바쁘기 때문이다.
what are you busy with?
무슨 일로 바쁘니?
Busy, drunk, having trouble hanging out with friends?
바쁘고, 술에 취해, 친구들과 어울리는 데 어려움을 겪고 계십니까?
Oh, come on.
오 어서.
Mom can cook a lot of delicious food.
엄마는 맛있는 음식을 많이 요리할 수 있어요.
I also make my kids’ favorite mixed vegetables.
아이들이 좋아하는 혼합 야채도 만들어요.
This doesn't have to be difficult. Because I won't go.
이것은 어려울 필요가 없습니다. 왜냐하면 나는 가지 않을 것이기 때문이다.
I will send you more money.
돈을 더 보내드리겠습니다.
You should go buy some new clothes and get some fresh air.
가서 새 옷을 사서 신선한 공기를 쐬어야 해요.
Stop watching old videos, they are so depressing.
오래된 비디오 시청을 중단하세요. 너무 우울합니다.
That's it.
그게 다야.
Just asking: Why is the murderer in my novel...
그냥 물어보세요: 내 소설에 살인자는 왜 나오는 걸까요...
Even if it’s only women?
여자만 있어도?
I have no idea.
나는 모른다.
An old aunt like me comes to write novels
나 같은 늙은 이모가 소설을 쓰러 온다
You must not find it strange, right?
이상하다고 생각하시면 안 되겠죠?
Just like any man in this world...
이 세상의 모든 남자들처럼...
can murder
살인을 할 수 있다
Any woman can kill a man. It's also cruel.
여자라면 누구나 남자를 죽일 수 있다. 그것은 또한 잔인하다.
I only choose stories...
난 스토리만 골랐는데...
I'm more familiar with it. Let's turn it into a novel.
좀 더 친숙한 데 소설로 바꿔보자.
If so, let's move on to the next question.
그렇다면 다음 질문으로 넘어가겠습니다.
(Author discussion with writer Gao Meishi)
( 작가 Gao Meishi와의 저자 토론)
This is your first novel. Published 1987
이것은 당신의 첫 번째 소설입니다. 1987년 출판
"small door"
"작은 문"
This is the teacher's only novel...
선생님의 유일한 소설이에요...
There is no murderer there
거기 살인자는 없어
Mr. Yin Ying's favorite novel is here.
Yin Ying 씨가 가장 좋아하는 소설이 여기에 있습니다.
Yes, it led me to this hell.
그래, 그게 나를 이 지옥으로 이끌었어.
A novel that I both love and hate.
내가 좋아하기도 하고 싫어하기도 하는 소설.
This story was written by a teacher when I was only nineteen years old.
이 이야기는 제가 열아홉 살이었을 때 선생님이 쓴 것입니다 .
Isn’t it boring to talk about the past?
과거 얘기하는 게 지루하지 않나요?
Rather than talk about this, I'd like to...
이 이야기를 하기보다는...
Introducing the most important people in my life now
지금 내 인생에서 가장 중요한 사람들을 소개합니다
over there in the back
저기 뒤쪽에
See that sparkly girl?
저 반짝이는 소녀 보이시나요?
She is a personal editor. I mentioned it before
그녀는 개인 편집자입니다. 아까도 언급했는데
Also my soul mate.
또한 내 소울메이트.
Most of my successes...
내 성공의 대부분은 ...
I got it because of her dedication.
나는 그녀의 헌신 때문에 그것을 얻었습니다.
I can not believe it. Who planned this event?
믿을 수 없어. 누가 이 행사를 계획했나요?
I haven't been able to write much lately.
최근에는 글을 많이 쓰지 못했습니다.
And asked me to answer nonsense questions.
그리고 말도 안되는 질문에 답해달라고 요청했습니다.
When do we talk about old novels?
우리는 언제 옛날 소설에 대해 이야기하나요?
Some novels have sold more than a million copies. There are more volumes
일부 소설은 백만 부 이상 팔렸습니다. 더 많은 볼륨이 있습니다
I'm still talking about my first bad piece.
나는 아직도 내 첫 번째 나쁜 작품에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
Oh, and look at your own work again.
아, 그리고 당신의 작품을 다시 한번 보세요.
do not you know?
몰랐 니?
How many people became fans because of the teacher's first novel?
선생님의 첫 소설로 인해 얼마나 많은 사람들이 팬이 되었나요 ?
This is me. who became the first fan
나야. 첫 번째 팬이 된 사람
If it weren't for the sentences in the teacher's novel, I would...
선생님 소설 속 문장만 아니었으면 ...
Hey, do you think I'm interested in her?
야, 내가 그 사람한테 관심 있는 것 같아?
So let's go back to the office, okay?
그럼 사무실로 돌아가자, 알았지?
Please take some of the pressure off me.
제 부담을 좀 덜어주세요.
Oh, my daughter.
아, 내 딸.
What?
무엇?
I'm going to start the car now.
이제 차의 시동을 걸겠습니다.
This kid is so cold.
이 아이는 너무 추워요.
Do I want more money?
나는 더 많은 돈을 원합니까?
I just want to see your face.
나는 단지 당신의 얼굴을 보고 싶습니다.
This doesn't mean...
이것은 의미하지 않습니다 ...
I rewatch the video because I have no money so I will die.
돈이 없어서 죽겠다 싶어서 영상을 다시 봅니다 .
Oh my god.
맙소사.
Oh, it's so expensive.
아, 너무 비싸요.
Hello
안녕하세요
Sorry to keep you waiting.
기다리게해서 미안합니다.
- Can I see number 36? - Can.
- 36번을 볼 수 있나요? - 할 수 있다.
What about restaurants?
레스토랑은 어떻습니까?
I made a reservation at the store across the street.
저는 길 건너편에 있는 매장에 예약을 했어요.
You can go as soon as Ena arrives.
에나가 도착하자마자 가셔도 됩니다.
I sent the address to Teacher Park.
박 선생님께 주소를 보냈어요.
Did you see the introduction I sent you?
제가 보낸 소개서 보셨나요?
Don't you see the dark circles under your eyes?
눈 밑에 다크서클이 보이지 않나요?
I read it all night until I couldn't sleep. It's really fun.
밤새도록 잠이 오지 않을 때까지 읽었습니다. 정말 재미있어요.
Slightly relieved.
약간 안도감.
This time, he won't be torn to pieces.
이번에는 조각조각 찢겨지지 않을 것이다.
She hates my job in many ways.
그 사람은 여러 면에서 내 일을 싫어해요.
No, Master, why do you say that?
아니 선생님, 왜 그런 말씀을 하시나요?
There will be a good response. Only after her verification.
좋은 반응이 있을 것입니다. 그녀의 확인 후에야.
So I can't really complain.
그래서 나는 정말로 불평할 수 없다.
But anyone can check and fix this problem.
하지만 이 문제는 누구나 확인하고 해결할 수 있습니다.
Of course, all writers are teachers.
물론 모든 작가는 교사이다.
Bring it with you.
그것을 가지고 오십시오.
It will go well this time, Master. I can feel.
이번에는 잘 될 거예요, 마스터. 나는 느낄 수있다.
It is often said that good shoes will take you to good places.
좋은 신발은 좋은 곳으로 데려다준다는 말을 자주 합니다 .
Why is she wearing those shoes?
그 사람은 왜 그 신발을 신고 있는 거죠?
-Run away- I want a pair.
-도망쳐- 나 한 켤레 갖고 싶어.
- What shoes? - let me see.
- 무슨 신발요? - 어디 보자.
Mother?
어머니?
-Stop. -Don't push.
- 그만해요 - 밀지 마세요.
- Don't push me. - Be careful.
- 밀지 마세요 - 조심하세요
It's like a flea market.
벼룩시장 같군요.
Just some stupid shoes on sale. Why all the fuss?
그냥 멍청한 신발이 세일 중이군요. 왜 이렇게 소란을 피우는 걸까요?
- What’s wrong with you? - bring it on.
- 무슨 문제 있어? - 가져오세요.
- Yes, this is the sixth one. - Sorry.
- 네, 여섯 번째예요 - 미안해요
Life is so miserable.
인생은 너무 비참합니다.
- Very beautiful - Size 6.5
- 매우 아름답습니다 - 사이즈 6.5
Even though people are poor, they still need to have a certain standard.
비록 가난하더라도 사람에게는 일정한 기준이 있어야 합니다.
You should remember this before you get older.
더 늙기 전에 이것을 기억해야 합니다.
- Mom - Oh.
- 엄마 - 아.
Are you OK?
괜찮으세요?
What should we eat today? I'm starving.
오늘 우리는 무엇을 먹을까요? 배고파 죽겠 어.
I may not have eaten anything yet. Because you have to follow your mom, right?
아직 아무것도 먹지 않았을 수도 있어요. 엄마를 따라야 하기 때문이죠?
I'm probably waiting for you, let's go.
아마 기다리고 있을 텐데, 가자.
Brother, let’s go first and talk after dinner.
형, 먼저 가서 저녁 먹고 얘기하자.
Yes
예
Oh my god.
맙소사.
oh
오
Mother
어머니
real
진짜
Are you crazy?
제정신이에요?
Aren't you afraid of cars?
당신은 자동차를 두려워하지 않습니까?
I'm hard of hearing. I've called several times.
나는 귀가 잘 들리지 않습니다. 나는 여러 번 전화했습니다.
Mom is thinking about this problem. How much did you spend today?
엄마는 이 문제에 대해 생각하고 있어요. 오늘 얼마를 쓰셨나요?
I know, don't raise your voice.
알아요, 목소리를 높이지 마세요.
I didn't raise my voice.
나는 목소리를 높이지 않았다.
Hey, cool, try this.
이봐요, 이거 한번 해보세요.
what else?
또 뭐야?
If it doesn’t fit, try it on quickly. Mom will take it to change.
맞지 않으면 빨리 입어보세요. 엄마가 가져갈 게요.
Do you want me to give it to you too?
내가 당신에게도 주길 바라나요?
No, talk about it later.
아니요, 나중에 얘기하세요.
- I don't want - oh, this child.
- 난 원하지 않아요 - 아, 이 아이.
He said I would try again later and got up.
그는 나중에 다시 시도하겠다고 말하고 일어났습니다.
I know, okay.
나도 알아, 알았어.
- Are you satisfied? - Perfect fit, right?
- 만족하시나요? - 딱 맞죠?
Or is it because your daughter is beautiful?
아니면 딸이 예뻐서 그런 걸까요?
The shoes look shiny.
신발이 반짝이는 것 같아요.
It is often said that good shoes will take you to good places.
좋은 신발은 좋은 곳으로 데려다준다는 말을 자주 합니다 .
Who would believe such a thing? It's just nonsense.
누가 그런 말을 믿겠습니까? 그것은 단지 말도 안되는 일입니다.
Hey, these are not cheap shoes.
아, 이거 싼 신발이 아니네요.
Mom doesn't buy it. From the store where the child met the mother, stand up and look.
엄마는 그것을 사지 않습니다. 아이가 엄마를 만난 가게에서 일어나서 보세요.
Mom went to their store and bought it at full price.
엄마가 가게에 가서 정가에 사셨어요.
This is good stuff.
이것은 좋은 것입니다.
I said nothing here.
나는 여기서 아무 말도 하지 않았다.
Who told you to buy it?
누가 사라고 했나?
I told my mother to take the money. Go buy some beautiful clothes for yourself?
나는 어머니에게 돈을 가져가라고 말했습니다. 가서 아름다운 옷을 사러 가시나요?
Mom has no place to show off.
엄마는 자랑할 곳이 없어요.
That is why.
그렇기 때문에.
So don't dress like this...
그러니까 이런 옷은 입지 마세요...
- What's this ?
- 이게 뭐죠 ?
How many times have I told you to throw it away?
버리라고 몇번이나 말했지?
Why do you love this decade-old vintage scarf?
이 10년 된 빈티지 스카프를 좋아하는 이유는 무엇인가요?
Look at other people around you.
주변에 있는 다른 사람들을 보세요.
Who wears such clothes? look.
누가 그런 옷을 입나요? 바라보다.
I should never have bought it for my mom in the first place.
애초에 엄마한테 사주지 말았어야 했는데.
I get it and my ears are going to explode. Don't shout.
이해하고 귀가 터질 것 같아요. 소리 지르지 마세요.
Do you embarrass your child so much?
당신은 당신의 아이를 그렇게 당황하게 합니까?
I only work with smart, level-headed people.
나는 똑똑하고 수준 높은 사람들과만 일합니다.
People like mothers are a laughingstock to their children.
어머니 같은 사람은 자식들에게 웃음거리가 됩니다.
Why do you say that?
왜 그런 말을 해?
But you know what?
하지만 그거 알아요?
Even if your child is wearing dirty shoes and an old-fashioned scarf
아이가 더러운 신발 과 구식 스카프를 입고 있어도
A mother never neglects her child.
엄마는 결코 아이를 방치하지 않습니다.
that's right...
좋아요...
No matter what your child wears or does. A mother never neglects her child.
아이가 무엇을 입든 무엇을 하든 상관없습니다. 엄마는 결코 아이를 방치하지 않습니다.
do you understand?
이해했나요?
And mom...
그리고 엄마...
The mother doesn't know how to play with her child either.
엄마도 아이와 놀아주는 법을 모릅니다.
Mother
어머니
then...
그 다음에...
If I didn't let my mother go like this...
엄마를 이대로 보내지 않았다면...
real
진짜
Will anything change?
뭔가 바뀔까요?
I don't play either.
나도 안 놀아요.
- Do you want this bag? - Yes.
- 이 가방을 원하세요? - 예.
I think there's plenty of time to make up for this.
아직 만회할 시간은 충분하다고 생각합니다 .
(Screenwriter Gao Meishu)
(각본가 가오메이슈)
(Sunday, May 9)
(5월 9일 일요일)
(Turn off the power)
(전원을 끕니다)
Oh, it's me. Did you have meal?
아, 나야. 식사하셨나요?
Because I'm still a mother.
왜냐하면 나는 아직 엄마이기 때문이다.
Because one person is a mother...
한 사람이 엄마이니까...
He will always be waiting for us no matter what.
그분은 무슨 일이 있어도 항상 우리를 기다리고 계실 것입니다.
Mother
어머니
(Invitation card to the wedding of Baek Hee-seop and Lee Sun-ae)
( 백희섭, 이순애 결혼식 초대장 )
Hello
안녕하세요
Yes, I'm talking.
응, 내가 말하는 거야.
But mom...
그런데 엄마...
my mother...
우리 엄마...
There seems to be a suicide note.
유서가 있는 것 같습니다.
Mother
어머니
in the past...
과거에...
I used to miss that day in this world. Don’t you have a mother?
나는 이 세상에서 그 날을 그리워하곤 했습니다. 당신은 어머니가 없나요?
Mother...
어머니...
Mommy mommy.
엄마 엄마.
I don't want it.
나는 그것을 원하지 않는다.
- Now on Earth - Mother
- 지금 지구에서는 - 어머니
"Mother"
"어머니"
Mother...
어머니...
When I say this word...
이 말을 하니까...
- No one answered - That's not true
- 아무도 대답하지 않았습니다. - 사실이 아닙니다.
(May 9, writer Gao Meishi)
(5월 9일 작가 가오메이시)
(I've lost my patience with you)
(나는 너에 대한 인내심을 잃었어)
(You may need to find another publisher.)
(다른 출판사를 찾아야 할 수도 있습니다.)
(delete)
(삭제)
Still can't contact your father?
아직도 아버지께 연락이 안 되시나요?
I don't understand why you come here?
왜 여기에 왔는지 이해가 안 돼요 ?
In this Wujing Village
이 우징 마을에서
I've never heard of it before.
나는 전에 그것을 들어 본 적이 없습니다.
And it's also far away from our home.
그리고 우리 집에서도 멀리 떨어져 있어요.
(Police Detective)
(경찰 수사관)
We still need to investigate further.
아직 더 조사해야 합니다.
But you should check this out.
하지만 이것을 확인해야합니다.
I think he intended to send it to his daughter.
딸에게 보내려고 했던 것 같아요.
(Father)
(아버지)
Father
아버지
Is that Yoon Young?
윤영이요?
Her father was in trouble again.
그녀의 아버지는 또다시 고민에 빠졌습니다.
I won't give in this time.
이번에는 포기하지 않겠습니다.
Do you know how many plates he broke?
그 사람이 몇 개의 접시를 깨뜨렸는지 아세요?
Ah what?
아 뭐?
Oh, don't puke there.
아, 거기 토하지 마세요.
really too much
정말 너무해
Oh my god.
맙소사.
Send me the account number and amount.
계좌번호와 금액을 보내주세요.
Compensate for all losses he has promised so far
지금까지 약속했던 모든 손실을 보상해 드립니다.
I'll forward it to you now.
지금 전달해 드리겠습니다.
I'm afraid you won't come.
당신이 오지 않을 까봐 두렵습니다.
No, I'm worried you won't come.
아니, 네가 안 올까봐 걱정돼.
I felt a little relieved.
나는 조금 안도감을 느꼈다.
who are you?
누구세요?
how do you know?
어떻게 알아?
You have to ask.
물어봐야합니다.
How do I know? You are not a bad person...
내가 어떻게 알아? 당신은 나쁜 사람이 아닙니다 ...
Since 34 years ago, or...
34년 전부터...
how could I know...
내가 어떻게 알아...
The night before being released...
풀려나기 전날 밤..
You will hang yourself.
당신은 목을 매게 될 것입니다.
I told you the answer last night.
어젯밤에 답을 말했어요.
I think I'll believe it. Are you talking nonsense?
믿을 것 같아요. 말도 안되는 소리를하고 있습니까?
Do you really want me to believe that you really went back in time?
당신 이 정말로 과거로 돌아갔다고 내가 믿기를 바라나요 ?
alright.
괜찮은.
Because I've been rotting in prison for thirty years.
왜냐하면 나는 30년 동안 감옥에서 썩어 있었기 때문입니다.
So I thought of making fun of it.
그래서 놀리려고 생각했어요.
I don't know about this. Real world, damn?
나는 이것에 대해 모른다. 현실 세계, 젠장?
There are still 16 years to go.
아직 16년이나 남았습니다.
I plan on going head to head. And retired at a young age
정면승부를 펼칠 생각입니다. 그리고 어린 나이에 은퇴
I will go fishing, read books...
낚시도 가고, 책도 읽고...
In such a quiet village I want to continue playing.
이런 조용한 마을에서 계속 놀고 싶다.
That used to be my dream.
그것은 내 꿈이었습니다.
This was the path I chose.
이것이 내가 선택한 길이었다.
But by 2037 , that is, 16 years later.
하지만 2037년 , 즉 16년 후가 됩니다.
I want to see my simple dreams come true. is this real?
나는 나의 소박한 꿈이 실현되는 것을 보고 싶다. 이거 진짜야?
I'm just going to check it out and come back.
그냥 확인해보고 다시 오겠습니다.
(Time Travel System, 2021)
(시간여행시스템, 2021)
(Time travel system, 2037)
(시간여행 시스템, 2037)
However...
하지만...
I can not do it.
나는 그것을 할 수 없습니다.
My dream cannot come true.
내 꿈은 이루어질 수 없습니다.
Because I died young
어렸을 때 죽었으니까
one year from now
지금부터 1년
I will die at the age of 35.
나는 35세에 죽는다.
Do you want to know about my death? What does this have to do with you?
내 죽음에 대해 알고 싶나요? 이것이 당신과 무슨 관련이 있나요?
because...
왜냐하면...
The villain who killed me is the real villain...
나를 죽인 악당이 진짜 악당이다...
In Serial Murder Case Yujingcun, 1987
1987년 유징춘 연쇄살인사건
how do you say?
어떻게 말해요?
What is that about...
그게 뭐야?
(Bangbang Tea House)
(방방찻집)
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(서울모 0508)
That was the symbol of the 1987 villain.
그것은 1987년 악당의 상징이었다.
It was also found at the scene of my murder.
그것은 내가 살해된 현장에서도 발견되었습니다.
Of course you are the first. police are looking for
물론 당신이 처음입니다. 경찰이 찾고 있어요
but you...
하지만 당신은...
He even died before me.
심지어 그는 나보다 먼저 죽었습니다.
You said you didn't kill anyone.
당신은 누구도 죽이지 않았다고 말했습니다.
can't stand injustice
불의를 참을 수 없다
The night before you were released, it was yesterday
네가 풀려나기 전날 밤, 그게 바로 어제였어
You hanged yourself in your cell.
당신은 감방에 목을 매었습니다.
impossible
불가능한
how do you know?
어떻게 알아?
That doesn't make sense at all, does it?
그건 전혀 말이 되지 않는데요, 그렇죠?
How can a dead man kill me?
죽은 사람이 어떻게 나를 죽일 수 있습니까?
So I decided to believe you were innocent.
그래서 나는 당신이 결백하다고 믿기로 결정했습니다.
how do you say?
어떻게 말해요?
Can I believe it?
믿을 수 있나요?
This is the real villain.
이것이 진짜 악당입니다.
Can we really find it?
정말 찾을 수 있을까요?
You have to get it.
당신은 그것을 얻어야합니다.
How did I drive off the road?
내가 어떻게 도로에서 운전을 했나요?
This is the only way. You and I will have a chance...
이것이 유일한 방법입니다. 당신과 나에게는 기회가 있을 것이다...
have a proper life
올바른 삶을 살아라
(To Yin Ying)
(인잉에게)
Yoon Young
윤영
I'm sorry I made you angry.
화나게 해서 미안해요.
And mom...
그리고 엄마...
The mother doesn't know how to play with her child either.
엄마도 아이와 놀아주는 법을 모릅니다.
After the children move out
아이들이 이사 나온 후
Mother
어머니
Mom couldn't help but lament that we were drifting apart
엄마는 우리가 멀어지고 있다는 사실을 한탄하지 않을 수 없었습니다.
Mom may be trying to appear angry.
엄마는 화가 난 것처럼 보이려고 노력하고 있을지도 모릅니다.
Oops, the frogs are singing.
앗, 개구리들이 노래를 부르고 있어요.
Son, grandson, daughter-in-law
아들, 손자, 며느리
let's get together
함께 해요
Singing all night long but no one wanted to listen.
밤새도록 노래를 불렀지만 아무도 듣고 싶어하지 않았습니다.
During this time, my mother no longer missed me. I couldn't do it as a kid.
이 기간 동안 어머니는 더 이상 나를 그리워하지 않았습니다. 나는 어렸을 때 그것을 할 수 없었습니다.
when the child was young
아이가 어렸을 때
My kids used to sing the frog song.
우리 아이들은 개구리 노래를 부르곤 했어요.
I will always play with you.
나는 항상 당신과 함께 놀 것입니다.
Even if my mother turns into a gray-haired grandma
엄마가 백발의 할머니가 되어도
I play with my mother every day.
나는 매일 엄마와 놀아요.
That's why I have to play...
이래서 놀아야지...
-Your little mouth used to talk all the time. -For me too. All right.
-네 작은 입은 항상 말을 하곤 했어. - 나도. 괜찮은.
Baby’s little hands are so cute
아기의 작은 손이 너무 귀여워요
Oh no, no.
아뇨, 아뇨.
Ouch!
아야!
If mom could travel through time and space
엄마가 시간과 공간을 여행할 수 있다면
Mom also wants to...
엄마도 그러고 싶어...
Go back to that time and hold those hands again
그때로 돌아가 다시 그 손을 잡아
cute little hands of child
아이의 귀여운 작은 손
Yoon Young
윤영
Mom will never forget.
엄마는 결코 잊지 못할 것입니다.
If only my mom could do it.
엄마가 할 수만 있다면.
Mom wants to play with her baby...
엄마는 아기랑 놀고 싶어하는데...
For the rest of my life , until my mother turns into a gray-haired grandma.
어머니가 백발의 할머니가 될 때까지 평생 .
From this mother who loves her children
자식을 사랑하는 이 어머니에게서
(Bangbang Tea House)
(방방찻집)
"Book" right?
"책" 맞죠?
(Book...)
(책...)
That is...
그건...
Yoon Young
윤영
Why didn't my mother answer the phone when she called me?
엄마가 나한테 전화했는데 왜 전화를 안 받으셨어요?
Before my mother passed away, she called my father three times.
어머니는 돌아가시기 전에 아버지에게 세 번이나 전화를 하셨습니다.
Are you ignoring your mother again?
또 엄마 무시하는 거야?
let's go.
갑시다.
We should start from here. Let's go find the children's mother.
우리는 여기서부터 시작해야 합니다. 아이들의 엄마를 찾으러 가자.
Where can mom go?
엄마는 어디로 갈 수 있나요?
How can we find mom?
엄마를 어떻게 찾을 수 있나요?
- Yunying- Dad.
- 윤잉- 아빠.
Do you know why I keep wanting to leave? Away from hometown
내가 왜 계속 떠나고 싶은지 아세요? 고향을 떠나
Because I hate seeing father and mother living together.
왜냐하면 나는 아버지와 어머니가 함께 사는 것을 싫어하기 때문이다.
That's why.
그렇기 때문에.
When we're together, we argue.
우리는 함께 있으면 논쟁을 벌인다.
Every time we quarreled my father then left the house.
우리가 말다툼을 할 때마다 아버지는 집을 나가셨습니다.
And mom will always wait for dad.
그리고 엄마는 항상 아빠를 기다릴 거예요.
I hate seeing this every day. To escape from there
이런거 매일 보는게 너무 싫다 그곳에서 탈출하려면
Even though I know in the end my mother will be alone.
결국 엄마는 혼자가 되리라는 걸 알면서도 .
But my mother said she missed me.
그런데 어머니는 내가 보고 싶었다고 하셨다.
If mom could go back in time
엄마가 시간을 되돌릴 수 있다면
Mom was stupid enough to say she would come find me again.
엄마는 나를 다시 찾으러 올 거라고 말할 정도로 멍청했어요.
I am...
그래요...
I want to go back in time. Dad, you can really go back.
나는 시간을 되돌리고 싶다. 아빠, 정말 돌아가실 수 있어요.
If I could turn back time
그때로 돌아 간다면
I would take the long way back.
나는 먼 길을 돌아갈 것입니다.
This way mom doesn't have to...
그러면 엄마는 그럴 필요가 없어...
love daddy
사랑해요 아빠
Or love me again
아니면 다시 나를 사랑해줘
Mom doesn't have to live with anyone...
엄마는 누구랑도 살 필요가 없어...
This makes my mother feel lonely and deceives her into waiting for a lifetime.
이로 인해 어머니는 외로움을 느끼게 되고 어머니를 속여 평생을 기다리게 됩니다.
I will make my mother happy...
엄마를 행복하게 해줄게...
Finish life by yourself
인생을 스스로 마무리하라
I will let mom live.
엄마를 살려줄게요.
But I can't.
하지만 난 할 수 없습니다.
Because it's impossible
불가능하니까
If you become obsolete, you will die.
낡아지면 죽습니다.
I'll buy you something better than this. Let's go to the mall together.
이것보다 더 좋은 걸 사줄게. 같이 쇼핑몰에 가자.
Expensive things are not necessarily good things, but this one is beautiful.
비싼 것이 반드시 좋은 것은 아니지만 이것은 아름답습니다.
This is my mom's favorite.
이것은 우리 엄마가 가장 좋아하는 것입니다.
The color suits you well too.
색깔도 잘 어울리시네요.
My daughter uses her salary. Start with your first part-time job
내 딸은 월급을 사용합니다. 첫 아르바이트부터 시작해 보세요
Come and buy it for me.
와서 사주세요.
With these little hands...
이 작은 손으로...
Oh, I'm disappointed with the money. But you can buy it for me.
아, 돈이 아쉬워요. 하지만 당신은 나를 위해 그것을 사줄 수 있습니다.
it's not a big deal.
그것은 큰 문제가 아닙니다.
My daughter goes to college near here.
내 딸은 이 근처 대학에 다니고 있어요.
I'm here to visit your university.
나는 당신의 대학을 방문하기 위해 여기에 왔습니다.
It is because of my daughter that I was able to go to college.
제가 대학에 갈 수 있었던 건 딸 덕분이에요 .
- You must be happy - Yes
- 행복해야지 - 예
Who knew this day would come?
이런 날이 올 줄 누가 알았겠어요?
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(서울모 0508)
Lay a piece of silk in my heart and stand at the end of your alley
내 마음에 비단 한 조각을 얹고 너의 골목 끝에 서라
I will welcome you with beautiful candles.
아름다운 촛불로 여러분을 맞이하겠습니다.
I turned into a butterfly and walked on the fragrant flower road
나비가 되어 향기로운 꽃길을 걸었어요
(Time travel system from 2021 to 1987)
(2021년부터 1987년까지의 시간여행 시스템)
I will fly and stop in your heart.
나는 날아가서 당신의 마음 속에 멈출 것입니다.
Our words become songs and poems.
우리의 말은 노래가 되고 시가 됩니다.
I'll sing to you after laying the carpet on my heart
내 마음에 융단을 깔고 너를 노래할게
Do you know what that feels like?
그게 어떤 느낌인지 아세요?
my carpeted heart
카펫 깔린 내 마음
Lay a piece of silk in my heart and stand at the end of your alley
내 마음에 비단 한 조각을 얹고 너의 골목 끝에 서라
I will welcome you with beautiful candles.
아름다운 촛불로 여러분을 맞이하겠습니다.
Wait a moment.
잠시만 기다려주세요.
ha!
하아!
Hey!
여기요!
That day, I brought the shoes my mother bought for me.
그날 나는 어머니가 사주신 신발을 가져왔다.
Where are they taking me?
그들은 나를 어디로 데려가는 걸까요?
(Seoul Mo 0508)
(서울모 0508)
(Time travel system from 2021 to 1987)
(2021년부터 1987년까지의 시간여행 시스템)
welcome
환영
(Celebrating the Seoul Olympic Games)
(서울올림픽 기념)
- Is there a problem? - This way, please.
- 문제가 있습니까? - 이쪽으로 오십시오.
Not that expensive.
그렇게 비싸지 않네요.
Come on, try it first.
자, 먼저 시도해 보세요.
It's well worth it.
그만한 가치가 있습니다.
Really good.
정말 좋다.
(teahouse haha)
(찻집 하하)
(Moon and Sun Gramophone)
(달과 태양의 축음기)
(vinyl records, cassette tapes, picture books)
(비닐 레코드, 카세트 테이프, 그림책)
Ouch!
아야!
excuse me
실례합니다
oh!
오!
May I?
나는 할 수있다?
Yes
예
Your forehead is bleeding too.
이마에서도 피가 나네요.
What's wrong with my shoulder?
내 어깨에 무슨 문제가 있는 걸까요?
It's not like that.
그렇지 않습니다.
I am fine.
괜찮아요.
Wait, what happened?
잠깐, 무슨 일이 일어난 거야?
Your face is also pale.
얼굴도 창백해요.
You should go to the hospital.
병원에 가보세요.
It's not because of you.
당신 때문이 아닙니다.
Just focus on yourself.
그냥 자신에게 집중하세요.
Don't break your word, do you understand?
약속을 어 기지 마십시오. 이해합니까?
Alas, am I exercising too hard?
아, 내가 운동을 너무 열심히 하는 걸까?
Almost gone
거의 사라졌어
(Baek Hee-seop)
(백희섭)
(moon night)
(달 밤)
(Family endurance walking competition Yujing Village, third time)
(가족 지구력 걷기대회 유징마을 제3회)
Even if she disappears far away
멀리 사라져도
like the wind blowing
바람이 부는 것처럼
Please stop for a moment.
잠시만 멈춰주세요.
We will also play the most modern songs.
우리는 또한 가장 현대적인 노래를 연주할 것입니다.
There is also a band performance at midnight.
자정에는 밴드 공연도 있습니다.
Sorry, I'm very tired today.
미안해요, 오늘은 너무 피곤해요.
Can you let me pass?
지나가게 해줄 수 있나요?
There is something going on with friends.
친구들과 무슨 일이 일어나고 있습니다.
It must have been painful to watch.
지켜보는 것이 괴로웠을 것입니다.
There is no reason to join the club. What's better than relieving stress?
클럽에 가입할 이유가 없습니다. 스트레스를 해소하는 것보다 더 좋은 것은 무엇입니까?
Why does everyone have to get in my way?
왜 모두가 내 앞을 가로막아야 합니까?
Are you interested?
관심이 있으신가요?
I heard the rewards are good.
보상이 좋다고 들었습니다.
If you finish third, you'll also get a Walkman.
3위를 하면 Walkman도 받게 됩니다.
My sister and I are going to participate in the competition tomorrow.
내 여동생과 나는 내일 대회에 참가할 예정이다.
That number was entered incorrectly, right?
그 번호 잘못 입력됐죠?
What day is tomorrow?
내일 무슨 요일이야?
"May 10th" Sunday
"5월 10일" 일요일
Does it have to be "Day 4" instead of "Day 3"?
"3일차 "가 아니라 "4일차"여야 합니까 ?
This is not that story, "1987."
이것은 "1987"이라는 이야기가 아닙니다.
It’s already 2021.
벌써 2021년이네요.
What's this? I am afraid.
이건 뭐죠? 나는 두렵다.
Is it really painful?
정말 고통스럽나요?
(May 10, 1987)
(1987년 5월 10일)
(Meet So Bangcha at Moon Night Club)
(문나이트클럽에서 소방차를 만나보세요)
(Moon Nightclub)
(문나이트클럽)
Brother, you go home, I won't disturb you anymore.
형님, 집에 가세요. 더 이상 방해하지 않겠습니다.
Is this really 1987?
지금이 정말 1987년인가요?
The 1988 Olympic Games will be held next year. I really do not know.
1988년 올림픽은 내년에 개최된다. 나는 정말로 모른다.
club?
클럽?
Do you really want to go to the club?
정말 클럽에 가고 싶나요?
Then...
그 다음에...
I think it's too late now. Shall we go to the amusement park?
지금은 너무 늦었다고 생각해요. 우리 놀이공원에 갈까?
Not really, but so what?
별로는 아니지만, 그래서 어떡하지?
We are still just students.
우리는 아직 학생일 뿐입니다.
"We are still just students."
"우린 아직 학생이에요."
Hey, Li Shanai wants to praise herself as an excellent student?
안녕하세요, Li Shanai는 자신을 훌륭한 학생이라고 칭찬하고 싶나요?
In a few days, we will be 20 years old.
며칠 후면 우리는 20세가 됩니다.
Go clubbing for a few months first. What would that look like?
먼저 몇 달 동안 클럽에 가보세요. 그것은 어떤 모습일까요?
And one more thing...
그리고 하나 더...
They had just been caught sniffing glue.
그들은 방금 접착제 냄새를 맡다가 잡혔습니다.
Will it really be okay?
정말 괜찮을까요?
Therefore...
그러므로...
So we have to take her with us.
그러니 우리는 그녀를 데려가야 합니다.
Please be careful when you talk to your mother this time .
이번에는 엄마와 이야기할 때 조심하세요 .
We went to study together...
같이 공부하러 갔는데..
Staying at your house all night, do you understand?
밤새도록 네 집에 있으면 알겠니?
I don't like lying.
나는 거짓말을 좋아하지 않습니다.
this
이것
Do we really have to take this girl with us?
정말 이 여자를 데리고 가야 하나요?
that's right.
좋아요.
She must be complicit. To keep our stories consistent
그녀는 공범임에 틀림없다. 우리의 이야기를 일관되게 유지하려면
Last time she told my mom we didn't travel together.
지난번에 그녀는 엄마에게 우리가 함께 여행하지 않았다고 말했습니다.
So I was beaten almost to death by my mother.
그래서 저는 어머니에게 거의 죽을 정도로 구타를 당했습니다.
I must die...
난 죽어야 해...
Before marrying Hae Sung hyung?
해성형 결혼 전?
understand
이해하다
But will you let this girl go on like this?
그런데 이 여자를 이대로 놔둘 건가요?
No more we don't want to be kicked out...
더 이상 우리는 쫓겨나고 싶지 않습니다...
From entrance to club
입구부터 클럽까지
Oh my God, this is...
맙소사, 이게...
what do I do?
나는 무엇을 해야 합니까?
(Quan Yingnuo)
(관잉누오)
This would say...
이것은 말할 것입니다 ...
This year is 1987?
올해가 1987년인가?
If you are sick, go to the hospital.
아프면 병원에 가세요.
Don't do this in front of someone else's store.
다른 사람 가게 앞에서 이러지 마세요.
real
진짜
If you're joking, you have to have boundaries.
농담이라면 경계가 있어야합니다.
Have I ever told you I'm not in the mood right now?
내가 지금 기분이 안 좋다고 말한 적 있나요?
Is this a filming location?
여기가 촬영장인가요?
Where are we now?
지금 우리는 어디에 있나요?
yes...
예...
This is Wujing Village.
우징마을 입니다.
I don't know what "shooting location" means?
"촬영 장소"가 무슨 뜻인지 모르시나요 ?
It doesn't matter.
그것은 중요하지 않습니다.
I can find the answer myself.
나는 스스로 답을 찾을 수 있다.
oh
오
what is that?
저게 뭐에요?
(Please check the connection and try again)
(연결상태를 확인하신 후 다시 시도해주세요)
No signal here?
여기 신호가 없나요?
Can't access the Internet here?
여기서는 인터넷에 접속할 수 없나요?
what is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
- no signal? - What signal?
- 신호 없음? - 무슨 신호요?
What's going on around here?
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
Brother, please come back , don't come back again.
형님, 제발 돌아와요 , 다시는 돌아오지 마세요.
Damn, I almost dug my own grave.
젠장, 내가 거의 내 무덤을 파버릴 뻔했어.
- Is it this one? - Yes.
- 이거요? - 예.
unless...
하지 않는 한...
- we look great - let 's go
- 우리 정말 멋있어 - 가자
damn it.
젠장.
Learn to watch horses and boats.
말과 보트를 관찰하는 법을 배우십시오.
Yes, sorry.
네 죄송합니다.
Oops, the frogs are singing.
앗, 개구리들이 노래를 부르고 있어요.
Son, grandson, daughter-in-law
아들, 손자, 며느리
let's get together
함께 해요
Singing all night long but no one wanted to listen.
밤새도록 노래를 불렀지만 아무도 듣고 싶어하지 않았습니다.
Mother
어머니
This is real.
이것은 진짜입니다.
Sorry, I'll explain everything.
미안, 내가 다 설명해줄게.
Yes
예
You're probably still in shock right now.
당신은 아마 지금도 충격을 받고 있을 것입니다.
But it's worse than you think.
하지만 생각보다 더 나쁩니다.
We just...
우리는 그냥...
Back in 1987.
1987년으로 거슬러 올라갑니다.
And there is no way...
그리고 방법이 없습니다 ...
You can go back.
돌아갈 수 있습니다.
We're stuck here.
우리는 여기에 갇혀 있습니다.
is this real?
이거 진짜야?
Yes
예
Oh my god.
맙소사.
Don't be too scared.
너무 겁먹지 마세요.
I will do everything...
내가 다 할게...
If this is the case...
만일이 경우라면...
It's true, damn.
사실이야, 젠장.
sorry.
죄송합니다.
are you laughing?
너는 웃고 있니?
(Thanks to actor Kim Hye-eun)
(배우 김혜은님 감사합니다)
(And actor Kim Hyun-mok who was invited to perform)
(그리고 출연자 로 초청받은 배우 김현목 )
(Time travel system from 2021 to 1987)
(2021년부터 1987년까지의 시간여행 시스템)
(my perfect stranger)
(나의 완벽한 낯선 사람)
This is real?
이게 진짜야?
Is my mother still alive?
우리 엄마는 아직 살아 계시나요?
- Mom - Don't do this.
- 엄마 - 이러지 마세요.
Do you want to hit me?
나를 때리고 싶니?
Mom, what's wrong? Why did I hit you?
엄마, 무슨 일이에요? 내가 왜 당신을 때렸어요?
Okay, we're going to start hitting. Youth is gone
좋아요, 타격을 시작하겠습니다. 젊음은 사라졌다
What are kids like you doing here?
너 같은 애들은 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
- Come here quickly - You are not a student of our school
- 빨리 오세요 - 당신은 우리 학교 학생이 아닙니다
Yes, that's you.
네, 바로 당신이에요
Why do you have to pretend not to know?
왜 모른 척 해야 하는 걸까?
Are you here to travel?
여행하러 오셨나요?
Why did you enter the club?
클럽에 왜 들어왔나요?
He suddenly looked at me...
그 사람이 갑자기 나를 쳐다보더니...
I don't know what your name is.
당신 이름이 뭔지 모르겠어요.
My name is Baek Hee-seop.
제 이름은 백희섭이에요.
(Conclusion)
(결론)
Where have you been so late?
이렇게 늦게까지 어디 있었어?
Yuting Village
유팅 마을
Wujing Village?
우징마을?
Yuting Village is your hometown?
Yuting Village가 당신의 고향입니까?
Why did you end up there all of a sudden?
갑자기 왜 거기까지 온 거야?
fit...
맞다...
Something needs to be resolved.
뭔가를 해결해야 합니다.
(my perfect stranger)
(나의 완벽한 낯선 사람)